Heather K. Botting

108 Rolling River Court Nashville, TN 37221

ABOUT ME

I am an efficient and confident content creator entering the field of data analytics. Over the last 4 years, my focus has been in the healthcare and legal industries. Prior to my current role, I worked in healthcare reporting, analyzing proprietary healthcare data to look for trends and draw conclusions from datasets. I am a fast learner and am eager to grow. I meet deadlines, keep track of tasks, am a believer in the power of to-do lists, and work well collectively as well as independently.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Nashville Software School | June 2022 Data Analyst Apprentice

Vanderbilt University | May 2017 B.A., Double Major in Economics and English Honor's English Program Participant Dean's List

Florida College | May 2014

A.A., Emphasis in Economics and English
Presidential Scholar
F.C. Women's Soccer Program Scholarship
Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society
Dean's List

Cincinnati Hills Christian Academy | June 2013 High School Diploma Valedictorian National Merit Commendation AP Scholar with Honor

CONTACT DETAILS

513-939-5860 heatherkaym@gmail.com GitHub LinkedIn

DATA EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

Nashville Software School

Intensive, real-world, project management-based training in data analytics using business intelligence and visualization tools to drive business decisions.

- · Role: Data Analyst Apprentice
- Status: Program completion expected in June 2022

Lahman Baseball

 Wrote SQL queries to create data stories around the shortest player in MLB history, the highest paid athlete from Vanderbilt and other statistics including pitching, batting and stolen bases in the MLB from 1871-2017.

2016 Tax Returns

- Created an interactive dashboard in Excel using lookups, offsets, and other advanced functions to show individual state-level data for elderly and lowincome populations as well as how states compared to the national picture.
- Provided implications of results and potential solutions.

Metro Nashville Police Calls

 Using Python, explored police call data to determine if living in a place where adverse events are more likely to occur results in lower satisfaction with police and feelings of safety, as reported by residents.

Nashville Marathon

 Using PowerBi, created an interactive dashboard exploring characteristics of the participants and provided key takeaways regarding trends and run times.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Search Engine Optimization research, analysis and full spectrum of content creation
- Advanced Excel capabilities, including lookups, pivot tables, and creating interactive dashboards
- Experience writing queries in SQL to answer specific questions across numerous large datasets
- Experience creating graphs and interactive dashboards in PowerBi and Tableau

WORK HISTORY

Content Manager

Waller Lansden Dortch & Davis, LLP

November 2018 to Present

- Responsible for the creation of content for areas of strategic focus, including healthcare and financial services.
- Manage the firm's SEO analysis, relationship with SEO service provider, and handle the entry of matters into the experience database.
- Work closely with business development managers, executive directors and attorneys to develop high-value content for clients, often with tight and competing deadlines.

Content Analyst

Decision Resources Group

November 2017 to November 2018

- Condense research and proprietary data into concise reports. Conduct research to create compelling content addressing various healthcare segments —health systems and hospitals, health plans, therapeutic areas, pharmaceuticals, government action, market and/or national trends, and M&A activity—for a readership of subject matter experts.
- Created earnings summaries detailing the financial condition of public healthcare organizations.

Worldwide Sales Enablement & Communications Intern

IBM

May 2015-May 2017

- Design event pages and materials, including editing HTML when needed, edit sales training documents, and create technical glossary for Cloud organization.
- Mange distribution lists and newsletters, and research and compile content for executive blogs.